Guide to the Cornell University Department Entomology and Limnology records,1909-1973.
Department Entomology and Limnology
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Department of Entomology and Limnology records, 1908-1975.
21-23-1461
New York State College of Agriculture.Dept. of Entomology and Limnology.
1.3 Cubic Feet.
Correspondence, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of the department; includes subject files, correspondence, and other material; also includes mss. and notes by George C. Embody, 1909, 1930-ca. 1945; and mss. by C. McC. Mottley, ca. 1940 on fisheries research.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of the department; includes subject files, correspondence, and other material; also includes mss. and notes by George C. Embody, 1909, 1930-ca. 1945; and mss. by C. McC. Mottley, ca. 1940 on fisheries research.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture.; Embody, George C.; Mottley, C. McC.
Subjects:
Entomology--Study and teaching.; Entomology--Research.; Limnology--Research.; Fisheries--Research.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collection #21-23-1587.
See also Cornell University Department of Entomology Records, #21-23-2133, http://resolver.library.cornell.edu/cgi-bin/EADresolver?id=RMA02133.
CONTAINER LIST
- Animal Populations Regulated to Carrying Capacity of Plant Host by Genetic Feedback-David Pimentel and A. Benedict Soana, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Pesticides and Ecology, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Pesticides and Food, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Utilizing Natural Controls by Reducing Insecticides and Planting Additional Acres-David Pimentel and Christine Shoemaker, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Food Production and the Energy Crisis-David Pimentel, L. Hurd, T. Bellotti, et al., 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- E-Population, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Ford Foundation Grant, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Ford Foundation Training Program at CU [Ecology of Pest Management], 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Mosquito Control-Some Perspectives-1. Fungus, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mosquito Control-Some Perspectives-1. Chemical Control 2. Juvenile Hormone Compounds 3. Competitive Displacement 4.Mosquito Feeding Fish, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mosquito Control-Some Perspectives-1. Parasitic Nematodes 2. Parasitic Pathogens 3. Hydra, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mosquito Control-Some perspectives-1. Genetic Control 2. Predators 3. Bacterial 4. Plant Control (larvicidal), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mosquito Control-Some Perspectives-Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Trips-Philippines, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Influence of Alfalfa Resistance on a Pea Aphid Population and Its Associated Parasites, Predators, and Competitors-David Pimentel and A. G. Wheeler, Jr., 1972 (?) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- The Role of Pesticides in the Control of Anthropod-Borne Diseases Among the Developing Nations of the World-1. Control 2. Discussion (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Information Folder-Dr. Pimentel, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- NIH Training-National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Research Proposal Evaluations, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Inter-University Training Program-Applied Ecology, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Alternative Methods of Mosquito Control (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Correspondence-New Jersey, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- National Science Foundation Grant-An Inter-University Program in Applied Ecology, July 1, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Mosquito Control: Some Perspectives for Developing Countries-January, 1973, Drafts (Box 1, Folder 24)
- New Perspectives in Mosquito Control Methods Suitable for Developing Countries (Box 1, Folder 25)
- New Perspective in Mosquito Control-Draft, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Papers, Drafts-Various Subjects--1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Manuscript Reviews-1971 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Manuscript Reviews-1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Pesticides and Pest Control, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Papers, Articles, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Motltley, C. M.-Manuscripts (1), 1931-1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Mottley, C. M.-Manuscripts (2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Bureau of Fisheries-Lists, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Embody, G. C.-Manuscripts, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Limnology, CU 2nd Semester-G. C. Embody, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- The Pattern of Biometrical Inquiry, December, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Lectures Notes-Trout Culture (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Biostatistics of Paul Lake Trout Population Egg Counts, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Piece of bark with names of those who went on the Cornell University Entomological Expedition to the Adirondack Mountains in Essex County, New York, August 19 - 27, of an unknown year, ca. 1920. (Box 2, Folder 9)